[Music]
for decades companies have automated
their accounts payable processes it's a
decade old problem all the way back to
the beginning of the computer
basically along the way different
technology has emerged that helps
companies streamline these processes
more ed better connectivity the
emergence of e invoicing and RPA and
even AI with optical character
recognition
OCR but even the combination of all of
these Technologies still don't do that
last mile of handling an invoice all the
stuff that a human would normally have
to do because the knowledge of the
accounting of how to register an invoice
correctly within your system for this
company in this industry in this country
so all of these questions today
typically needs to be handled by u a
human or they rely on on some tedious
mapping and setup that relies on data
being the same every time you receive a
certain
invoice this is a great case for
generative AI to solve we're happy to
introduce the payables agent the agent
that will streamline this accounting
payables process from start to
finish this is a great case for
generative AI generative AI is able to
unlock that last mile of accounting
knowledge that is typically needed to
process an invoice to
completion we imagine that the agent is
able to automate the entire flow from
receiving invoices from various channels
to ending up with a posted
invoice and accounting knowledge can be
applied at various stages across this
process you can also imagine we could
use AI to ask questions like is this
even a real invoice this is fraud is
there any anomalies how do we typically
handle this invoice in this company
and so on there are many many different
use cases many places where we can apply
intelligence now it's important to say
that even though this is an agent that
ideally could be automated 100% it's
designed for human
oversight we can decide and you can
decide where to bring in humans into the
loop where it adds value that is
subjective you might find Value in being
involved in certain decisions and we
might think there's value in some other
decisions we intend to make this
configurable so you can decide where to
be in the
loop to make this story a reality to
make the PES agent a reality we needed
to do some work on some building blocks
inside business Central the first one of
those is the new e doent connector for
Microsoft
365 it's a connector that you enable
through an e doent
service that enables you to import p PDF
attachments from a Microsoft 365 mailbox
or from SharePoint or from one drive
that gives you great options for
sourcing PDF invoices from these
channels another component we've been
working on is a new inbound e doent list
page this is your go-to page for every e
doent that you receive whether they come
in through SharePoint or Outlook or
electronic invoicing even it's important
to say here that the accounting
intelligence that we buil into to this
agent not only support PDFs it also
supports any other incoming vendor
invoice from E invoicing channels for
example the third thing we are building
as well to support the agent is a new
purchase document draft page this page
is where the agent will suggest how to
register the invoice where it will
suggest if you need to defer an expense
or split up an expense uh across
departments and so on it's also here you
get a preview of the PDF that you can
view in full screen or in the fact box
as shown here we may do some adjustments
to this page as it's in early stages
right now so this is where the bulk of
our development is at the moment but
this page is where users or agents can
go and assess a draft invoice and then
decide to finalize it so it becomes a
real purchase invoice document
all of these components are necessar to
build the payables agent
story but it's still in development we
aim for this agent to be available for
public preview somewhere in the second
half of 2025 with the scope of features
you see here one of the most important
things here is the intelligent
accounting that we built into the agent
basically taking the accounting
knowledge that typically reside in the
minds of bookkeepers and accountants and
learning from
that we want to be able to create
purchase invoices to begin with and we
want to make it easy for you to
configure human in the loop moments but
we also know it cannot stop there we
need to have a good story for supporting
other e doents like the E invoices I
mentioned before and we also definitely
want to support purchase order matching
so you get an invoice in and you map it
to purchase orders and do that three-way
matching that we all love and of course
approving
invoices is a crucial part for eyes
approval or whatever is a good fit in
your business we want to be able to
support that as well with an easy way to
see the original PDF
document and there we hope to bring some
scenarios alive that also enables you to
approve outside of business
inal a lot of great things to come with
the pbl's agent stay tuned for more
information